It was an age of war.
Relying only on his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man
is not a wandering samurai of today.
Conditioner and treatment.
What's the difference?
Isn't rinsing enough?
Can I help you?
Sorry.
My wife asked me to buy this.
CONDITIONER
TREATMENT
Yes, this is the product.
-Then I'll take these.
-Yes, sir.
-Our men's care is popular, too.
-I'm fine.
Quick, retreat.
I'm going to take a detour.
MARUNI PRODUCE NAKANOBU STORE
-Pork, please, 400 grams.
-Yes.
-Three hundred grams of fried chicken...
-Sure.
-and 200 grams of ground chicken.
-OK.
A smell that reminds me of the old days.
What could it be?
Croquettes!
After retiring,
he lost his title as a corporate employee
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story is about
a normal 60-year-old man
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
CROQUETTES OF THE HEART
Back in middle school...
there was a butcher...
called Tochigiya near my school.
-My very first croquette...
-Excuse me.
cost 20 cents.
No, 15 cents.
-Exact change.
-Yes.
-Senpai. Thanks for treating us.
-Thanks for treating us.
Go stand guard, Kasumi.
-Yes.
-Hurry up.
We'd be in trouble
if we got caught,
so we stood guard
and bought them quickly.
-Kasumi, that's enough.
-Yes.
-Two croquettes.
-Thank you.
-Four croquettes.
-Four, okay.
One croquette and one fried meat cake.
Yes, yes. Please, wait in line.
So, two for the first order?
-Yes.
-They look so delicious.
The man at Tochigiya...
knew we weren't allowed
to eat on the way home.
So, he wrapped them in paper
so no one would find out.
Thanks, as always.
So we can eat right away,
there was a bottle of sauce
on the counter.
We put on as much sauce as we wanted...
and bit into the hot croquettes.
After our club activities, we were hungry.
We also felt excited doing something
we weren't supposed to do.
I'll never forget how delicious they were.
All right. I'm going to do it again
after all these years.
Croquettes on the way home.
CHEESE
CRAB CREAM
Not this one.
MATSUZAKA BEEF CUTLET
Looks good, but pricey.
CROQUETTE
This is it.
-Excuse me.
-Yes. What would you like?
-The one dollar croquette, please.
-How many?
If I say only one
she might think I'm a stingy guy.
-Two, please.
-Yes, two.
I showed off for no reason.
Okay, that will be two dollars.
-Okay.
-Do you have sauce?
Yes, we do.
20 CENTS
-Is this it? I'll take one.
-Sure.
Two croquettes and a sauce.
Two dollars twenty cents.
-Exact change. Thank you.
-So hot!
Don't burn yourself. Thank you very much.
-Thanks.
-Thanks! Please, come again!
Fresh croquettes and beer.
Not bad.
No. I mean, that's great.
But beer in the middle of the day?
Why do I feel so guilty?
It's ice cold!
Okay...
where should I eat them?
What are you guys doing?
-Run!
Wait right there!
-The usual place!
-OK!
The roof of a building near the school.
That was our hiding spot.
That's right!
Enjoying croquettes and beer
with a good view
while it's still light outside.
This is something that
a middle-school student can't do.
There were many places like this...
when I was a kid.
If no one stops it,
everyone's heart will turn bad.
Okay.
Let's call Heart Ranger!
One, two...
Heart Ranger!
That's the Ferris wheel.
Want to ride it?
Do you want to eat
before we go on the rides?
Or the rides first?
Let's go on the Ferris wheel first.
Pick a color.
Is this a bit inappropriate?
But if I just wait,
the beer will get warm.
The fresh croquettes will get cold, too.
Oh well.
Guess I'll give up on eating here.
Delicious!
-Hey, kid.
-Don't look!
Want some?
Delicious!
Delicious.
Here we go. Oh, I'm full.
Here we go.
A samurai wouldn't worry
if he's being inappropriate or not.
Speaking of...
Us, too, back then...
never cared about that either.
For eating delicious food,
it doesn't matter
if I'm inside or out.
Eating when I want, where I want,
what I want!
Sauce is a must for croquettes.
This is it! This! The best combination!
It's delicious!
I'll finish it all before I even know it.
When I was working...
I always carried a heavy bag.
I was too busy working
to notice it was dark out every day.
But, now...
The grown-up version of eating out.
Banzai!
SHIZUKO
Hello.
Are you still shopping?
Shopping?
Conditioner and treatment.
I asked you to get them.
I bought them.
I've never been inside a salon.
I got a bit self-conscious.
Are you still near the shopping arcade?
Yes, I'm there.
I feel bad asking,
but did you get chicken thigh
at the butcher?
About 300 grams.
-Butcher shop?
-I'm going to cook it tonight. Thanks.
I got it.
All right...
I'm going.
Here we go.
Chicken thigh, 300 grams.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Fifty percent off starting now!
All items 50 percent off! Try some!
-Welcome!
Maybe I should take this chance
and buy the Matsuzaka fried meat cakes.
Welcome!
-Matsuzaka beef.
-All items half off.
The middle-school me would
have loved it.
Welcome. What would you like?
I ended up buying
more normal croquettes.
But that's okay.
This is what I wanted.
They may look and taste simple,
but they are still special
and full of memories.
I'm sure there's a food for everyone...
that's like what this croquette is to me.
Subtitle translation by
Hoday Stearns